STEVEN HAWKINS PAPERS (APAP188) 1991-2003
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Meeting Subject Files, 1995-2003; 1; 2
  - Meetings, 2001 March-2001 April (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Next Generation Leadership Reunion Planning Meeting, 2001 March
    - Reparations Discussion Howard University, 2001 April
    - Death Penalty Focus Annual Awards Dinner, Los Angeles, 2001 April
    - University of Texas Symposium, Austin, TX, 2001 April
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, New York City, 2001 April
    - National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Board Retreat, 2001 April
  - Meetings, 2001 May-2001 June (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bavarian-American Academy, Germany, 2001 May
    - Murder Victims' Families Reconciliation Conference, Boston, 2001 June
    - Together Against the Death Penalty, Strasbourg, FL, 2001 June
  - Meetings, 2001 July (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - G12 Amnesty International Follow-up Meeting, 2001 July
    - Seniors Group Meeting, 2001 July
    - Airlie Conference, 2001 July
    - Pre-U.N. World Conference Against Racism, Washington, D.C., 2001 July
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, 2001 July
  - Meetings, 2001 August-2001 December (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - G-12 Meeting, 2001 August
    - Human Rights Conference Call, 2001 October
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, 2001 October
    - Yale/Pierson College Master's Tea, 2001 November
    - Missouri Presentations, 2001 November
    - Soros Justice Fellowship Selection Committee, 2001 November
    - Human Rights Meeting, 2001 December
    - Youth Justice Funding Collaboration, 2001 December
  - Meetings, 2002 January-2002 February (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Conference on Imam Jamil A. Al-Amin, 2002 January
    - Death Penalty Information Center, 2002 January
    - Little Rock Meeting, 2002 January
    - University of Pittsburgh, 2002 January
    - Death Penalty Information Center Ad-Hoc Quarterly Meeting, 2002 February
    - New England Meetings, 2002 February
    - New Voices, 2002 February
    - New York University School of Law Center for International Studies Conference, 2002 February
    - Together Against the Death Penalty, 2002 February
  - Meetings, 2002 March-2002 April (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Oregon Criminal Defense Lawyers Association, 2002 March
    - Death Sentence Conference, Chicago, 2002 March
    - HUBCU Initiative Roundtable, Atlanta, 2002 March
    - American University Homophobia in the Courtroom Conference, 2002 March
    - California Meetings, Working Assets, 2002 April
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, 2002 April
  - Meetings, 2002 May-2002 July (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Juvenile Justice Funders Briefing, 2002 May
    - United Nations Second World Congress on Human Rights, 2002 May
    - Columbia Law School Bringing Human Rights Home Conference, 2002 June
    - National Summit on the Impact of Incarceration on African American Families and Communities, 2002 June
    - WABC Interview, New York City, 2002 July
    - Ending Exceptionalism Caucus, Washington, D.C., 2002 July
    - Open Society Institute, New York City, 2002 July
    - Legislative Roundup Workshop Airlie Conference, 2002 July
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, New York City, 2002 July
    - NCSL Briefing, Denver, 2002 July
    - Rainbow/PUSH Coalition Conference, Chicago, 2002 July
  - Meetings, 2002 August-2002 October (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Nashville, TN Roundtable Discussion, 2002 August
    - Francine Vernon Reception, 2002 September
    - New Yorkers Against the Death Penalty Meeting, Albany, NY, 2002 September
    - Capital Punishment Washington, D.C. Briefing, 2002 September
    - Tom Franck Tribute Conference, New York City, 2002 October
    - Atlantic Philanthropies, New York City, 2002 October
    - Sacco and Vanzetti Conference, New Haven, CT, 2002 October
    - The Exonerated Talk Back Play, 2002 October
  - Meetings, 2002 November-2002 December (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Boston University Great Debate, 2002 November
    - Indiana Information Center on the Abolition of Capital Punishment Coalition, 2002 November
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, 2002 November
    - Cornell University Workshop, 2002 December
    - Soros Justice Fellowship, 2002 December
    - Juvenile Death Penalty Conference, 2002 December
    - Southern Human Rights Organizers, Network Conference, 2002 December
  - Meetings, 2003 January-2003 April (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Washington Forum on the Juvenile Death Penalty, 2003 January
    - Columbia Law School, Litigating U.S. Human Rights Cases Before the Inter-American Human Rights Commission, 2003 January
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, New York City, 2003 February
    - Youth Justice Funding Collaborative Conference Call, 2003 February
    - Death Penalty Abolition Institute, Atlanta, 2003 March
    - New York University Awards Program, 2003 April
    - Next Generation Leadership Reunion, Houston, TX, 2003 April
  - Meetings, 2003 May-2003 August (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, New York City, 2003 May
    - New York Law Day, Yonkers, NY, 2003 May
    - Tides Foundation Death Penalty Mobilization Fund Conference Call, 2003 May
    - Congressional Black Caucus Policy Forum, Washington, D.C., 2003 May
    - Human Rights Institute Columbia Law School Panel, 2003 June
    - Ford Foundation Meeting, 2003 June
    - Global Youth Leadership Program, 2003 June
    - International Human Rights Funders Group, New York City, 2003 July
    - NAACP Legal Defense Fund Airlie Conference, 2003 July
    - Death Penalty Information Center Board Meeting, New York City, 2003 August
- Case Files, 1991-2002; 2; 1.2
  This series contains police files, amicus briefs, court briefs, witness testimony, memoranda between defense attorneys and prosecuting attorneys, and biographical information pertaining to death row inmates. It also includes memos and notes relating to the actions taken on behalf of these persons by Steven Hawkins and other members of the National Coalition Against the Death Penalty. The inmates included in this series are Mumia Abu-Jamal, Delma Banks, Jr., Wilburn Dobbs, Reginald Clemons, Clarence Allen Lackey, T. Makawanyane and Mchunu, Kenneth Reams and Keith Versie.
  The Abu-Jamal folders hold copies of court documents including a writ of certiorari and supplementary materials and a memorandum and order. This case is listed as Mumia Abu-Jamal v. Martin Horn and Connor Blaine, District Attorney for Philadelphia County, before the United States Court of Appeals.
  The Delma Banks Jr. folders consist of court documents including: brief; petitioners proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law; Respondent Johnson's Original Answer; Motion for Summary Judgment, and Brief in Support; Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus By a Person in State Custody; Conclusions of Law; NAACP statistics sheet; NAACP Legal Defense Fund attorney work product memorandum; National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Perspective; anti-terrorism bill; "Innocence and the Death Penalty" Staff Report by the Subcommittee on Civil, and Constitutional Rights Committee on the Judiciary. This case is listed as Delma Banks, Jr. v. Gary Johnson, Director, Texas Department of Criminal Justice, Institutional Division, Civil Action NO. 6.96-CV-220.
  The Reginald Clemons folder holds the court documents of Reginald Clemons v. State of Missouri Appellants statement, brief, and argument. The Clarence Allen Lackey folder also holds court documents including Clarence Allen Lackey v. State of Texas Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the Texas Court of Criminal Appeals.
  The Wilburn Dobbs folder holds a copy of a news clipping from the Supreme Court Reporter and a brief in opposition on behalf of respondent. The case is listed as Wilburn v. Walter D. Zant, Warden, before the Supreme Court.
  The Kenneth Reams folders hold a memoranda, Motion for Leave to Proceed in forma pauperis, interviews, correspondence, case of Terry Sims v. State of Arkansas, Response to Petition for Rehearing, Motion for Entry of Appearance, Petition for Stay of Mandate, Arkansas Code of 1987, and Brief of Appellee for the Appellant.
  The South African folders hold information about T. Makawanyane and Mchunu including a Memorandum of Law in Support of Appellants' Position in Makawanyane & Mchunu v. State submitted by the NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Funds and Human Rights Watch, as well as a copy of the South African constitution and applicable laws.
  The Keith Versie folders are the most comprehensive of all of the case files. The folders include: witness and defendant statements and evidence; procedural history; statement of Viola Scott, mother of defendant; defendant statement; notes; state's order of proof list; witnesses; psychological report; information about the transfer from juvenile to adult court; Footlocker store information; Tennessee Rules of Criminal Procedure; viewing of evidence in property room; ballistics evidence; criminal court files including notes, obituary of victim, and floor plan of murder location; the statements of Henry Bridgeforth, Handel Durham, and Michael Cohan who were the attorneys and investigator; statements of witnesses Tony Lewis Harris and Dennie Wayne Dobbins; police investigation file; and the motion for continuance. Also included are investigator and witness statements for Michael Cohan, Sherre Brown, Officer Buchanan, Sgt. J.D. Carroll, George Coleman, Taffice Dodson, Chet Dunlap, Officer Michael R. Faulkner, Sgt. R.L. Franks, Chris Graves, Dorothy Gupton, Latonya Hardin, Tony Lewis Harris, J.B. Herin, Captain Hewlett, Officer Jackson, Debra Johnson, Sgt. J.D. Kelly, Laura Knipp, Sgt. C.E. Logan, R.D. Lomax, Dawn Lusk Eberle, Sgt. R.W. McWilliams, Mike Matthews, Genivieve Regina Mandamin, Leslie Mozingo, Lt. L.H. Nelson, Sgt. D.R. Peterson, David Raybin, Joe Rike, R.D. Roleson, Sgt. Roten, William Rouse, Viola Scott, Barry K. Schultz, Herschel Smith, Mary Louise Smith, Shannon Smith, Andre Stepter, Charles Sullivan, D.M. Swauncey, Wyley Taylor, Sgt. Tillman, Mary Walker, R.O. Watson, Elizabeth Wilbanks, L.A. Wilder, Howard Williams, Sgt. S. Williams, Charles Wilson, Michael Wofford, Martha Wofford, K. Wong, and Ron Yarbrough.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Delma Banks, Jr. v. Gary Johnson, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Banks, Delma, Jr., Findings of Fact and Supplementary Material, 1993; 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Wilburn Dobbs v. Walter D. Zant, 1992; 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Reginald Clemons v. State of Missouri, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clarence Allen Lackey v. State of Texas, 1994 October (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Makawanyane & Mchunu v. State, Amicus Brief, 1995 January (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Makawanyane & Mchunu v. State, Constitution of the Republic of South Africa Bill, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Makawanyane & Mchunu v. State, Constitutional Court of the Republic of South Africa, Judgment, State v. T. Makawanyane, 1995 February-1995 June (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kenneth Reams v. State of Arkansas, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Kenneth Reams v. State of Arkansas, Abstract and Brief, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Kenneth Reams v. State of Arkansas, Abstract and Brief, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Versie, Keith, Defendant and Witness Statements, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Versie, Keith, Evidence and Court Files, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Versie, Keith, Investigator and Witness Statements, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 20-26)
  - Versie, Keith, Motion for Continuance, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Versie, Keith, Police Investigation File, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Versie, Keith, Witness and Defendant Statements and Evidence, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)